Manisha Baluja

Sr. User Experience Analyst

Lansdale, PA - Email me on Indeed: indeed.com/r/Manisha-Baluja/93a8b367791d9861

HFI Certified Usability Analyst with 8 years of experience as UX Lead in both agile and waterfall engineering teams. Adept at understanding and communicating the story that drives the design of a product.

I have lead complex user experience activities including user research, user workflows, information architecture, wireframes, storyboards, interactive prototypes and usability testing; for various projects throughout the design and development life cycle.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Sr. User Experience Analyst

Nagarro (at client location LUTRON) - Coopersburg, PA - 2010 to Present

- Perform and lead moderate to complex user experience activities that include user research through interviews.
- Defining personas, use cases and scenarios.
- Creating user workflows, information architecture, low- and hi-fidelity wire frames.
- Propose design concepts using storyboards and interactive prototypes.
- Act as the user-advocate during the development process, subjecting early-stage designs to usability testing or expert review.
- Partner with development groups and graphic designers to provide UI guidance and assure correct implementation.
- Perform usability testing with actual users; interpret user feedback and insights to improve the user experience.
- Create and document user interface guidelines and standards, best practices, design patterns, and project templates.
- Promote UX thinking by provide UX training for groups outside the User Experience team.

Manager Online Product

Yatra Online Pvt. Ltd - Gurgaon, Haryana - 2008 to 2010

Analyze requirements, create specification documents and develop information architecture.

- Design functional flows and create low and high fidelity prototypes (wireframes).
- GUI prototypes to communicate functional specifications and heuristic evaluations.
- Ensure the development of solution with the help of development engineers.
- Validate user experience through testing.
- Monitor the progress of the project and take overall responsibility of the project delivery.
- Usability recommendations for existing and new features.

Asisstant Manager Product

TimesJobs.com - Delhi, Delhi - 2006 to 2008

Creating requirement specification document.

- Low and high fidelity prototypes (wireframes) of web applications.
- Information Architecture and Design.
- Usability recommendations for existing and new features.
- · Ensure the development of solution with the help of development engineers and Project

Management.

Software Testing Professional

Keane India Ltd - 2005 to 2006

Worked on an Automation Testing Project (3 months) using WinRunner.

Officer

The Times of India - 2004 to 2005

Worked with TimesClassifieds & TimesJobs team.

EDUCATION

Certified Usability Analyst

Human Factors International 2009 to 2009

Master of Computer Application in Human Factors

Sikkim Manipal University 2008

Bachelor of Computer Application

Maharishi Dayanand University 2005

SKILLS

User Research through interviews, persona creation, user scenarios, user workflows, information architecture, wireframes, storyboards, paper prototyping, interactive prototypes, expert reviews, usability testing. Using Balsamiq, Visio, Adobe Illustrator, Adobe Edge Animate.